Guide to the Filippo Tommaso Marinetti Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Letters by BENEDETTA CAPPA MARINETTI, 1921-1944; Series II; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Zátkova, Rougena
    - [1922] Jun 20 4 p. (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Letters to and about Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, 1898-1970; Series III; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  - Empty envelopes addressed to FTM
    - n.d.; 1898?; 1902 Jan 10; 1904 Dec 20; 1906; 1907 Apr 27; 1908 Jan 21 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - 1908? Jun 17 Valere Bernard written in upper right; 1908 Jul 23; 1909 Sep 25; 1942? Sep?; 1944 Oct 22
  - Anonymous letters to FTM
    - [1906? Aug?] 2 p. je suis heureux de vous envoyer le poème...; [1909 Jul 31] 1 p. Merci, merci, merci, ce n'est...; 1924 Nov 23 Onore a voi, grande amico!... Telegram; 1929 Sep 9 Tutta la notte ho sognato... card (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Unidentified Letters to FTM and BCM
    - n.d. Grazie infinite del gentile invio... 1 p.; n.d. Il periodo che dovrebbe essere... 4 p.; n.d. Salute. Debbo insistere nell'invito... 2 p.; n.d. Non potendo-come? al solito?... 2 p.; May 25 Postcard Nov 5 Je n'ai pas encore pu lire le Roi Bombance... 2 p.; 1906 13 Grazie della mia affettuosa lettera... 1 p. Incomplete: top part only (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - 1908 Jul 22 Postcard; photograph of G. Kahn on verso; 1909 Nov? 9 3 p. In French; 1909 Aug 12 2 p.; 1909 Aug 21 3 p. In French; [1912 Nov 19] Postcard; [1914 Dec 26] Postcard; 1918 Dec 15 1 p.
    - 1922 Sep 28 2 p.; [1924? Nov?] Impossibilitato ad intervenire... 1 p.; TLS 1924 Nov 14 Postcard; 1924 Nov 20 1 p. TLS; 1924 Nov 22 1 p. TLS; 1924 Nov 22 1 p.; [1924] Nov 29 1 p.
    - 1929 Mar 22 Dalle amiche... 1 p.; 1929 Mar 22 A nome de futuristi 1 p.; 1929 Mar 24 1 p. In French; 1935 Oct 16 card.; 1939 Dec 31 card; In French; [1940 Sep 20] Postcard; 1942 Sep 23 card.; [1944 Dec] Non è necessario che io vi dica con quanto... 1 p. Condolence letter to BCM.
  - Académie Pichetti, Rome to FTM
    - 1912 Dec 22 1 p.; 1913 Apr 25 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Acito, Alfredoto FTM
    - 1924 [Nov?] 21 Venerdì 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Acquaviva, Giovanni to FTM
    - n.d. pregato Brizio... Postcard; n.d. che mi dite di... Postcard; signed also by Farfa.; n.d. Contraccambio saluti... Postcard; 1940 [Sep] ho la vostra del... 2 p. Signed also by Anna Viva.; [1940 Sep 28] Postcard (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - 1940 Oct 7 4 p. TLS; 1942 Aug 2 p. Signed also by Anna Viva.; 1942 Sep Dopo una salita al... 1 p.; 1942 Sep Ricevuto la vostra... 2 p. Signed also by Anna Viva and Giuliana Traverlo.; 1942 Oct 17 1 p.; 1944 Mar 16 Postcard, typed and signed; 1944 May 30 Postcard
    - 1944 Jun 24 Postcard; includes 5 lines written and signed by Farfa.; 1944 Jun 28 Postcard; 1944 Aug 23 Solo oggi Ricevo... Postcard; 1944 Aug 23 Lunghe soste... Postcard; 1944 Aug 23 oggi 3 cartoline vostre... Postcard; 1944 Oct 31 2 p.; 1944 Nov 4 2 p. Accompanied by a clipping (glued on postcard "I'Quarti d'ora di poesia" from Il Lavoro, 4 Nov 1944.
    - 1944 Dec 4 1 p. Enclosure: postcard.; 1944 Dec 9 1 p. Enclosure: "Con vivo successo si è svolto il 41o. 'Convegno di poesia"' and "La mostra decorative di Giovanni Acquaviva" Il Lavoro 6 Dec 1944.
  - Adalberto of Savoia, Duke of Bergamo to FTM
    - 1937 Mar 1 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Adam, Juliette to FTM
    - 1908 Jul 14 2 p. In French (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Adam, Paul to FTM
    - n.d. J'ai vu Madame de Noiailles... 1 p.; 1905 Jul 22 Postcard (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Agencia Americana, Rio de Janeiro to Agamerican (Agencia Americana), Genoa
    - 1926 May 15 Telegram; 1926 May 19 2 p. Telegram; 1926 May 21 Telegram; 1926 May 23 2 p. Telegram; the only telegram stamped by the sender.; 1926 May 28 Telegram; 1926 May 31 Telegram; 1926 Jun 7 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Agostino, Alfredo de, to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Aicard, Jean to FTM?
    - No year Oct 15 card, in French (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Akademos, Revue mensuelle d'Art libre et de Critique to FTM
    - 1909 Jul 5 1 p. Signed by (Ibsen) Fersen (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Alasonatti
    See: Box 15, folder 953
  - Albert-Birot, Pierre to FTM
    - 1919 Feb 25 Postcard (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Albertini, Alberto
    - n.d., calling card. (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Albrizzi to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Alfano, Franco to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Alfieri, Dino to FTM
    - [1936 Oct 26?] Micup punto per... Telegram; 1936 Nov 7 1 p. TLS; 1937 Mar 1 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Allemary, Jeanne (Jean Maldz) to FTM
    - n.d. Ai-je besoin de vous dire... 3 p. (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Almeida, Renato
    - n.d. Para recordar a sua passagem... card, removed from Almeida, Renato, Velocidade Rio de Janeiro [1932] (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Altomare, Libero, pseud.
    See: Box 12, folder 677
  - Amati, Luigi to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram; signed also by Angelo Mazzoni and Luigi Barsi (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Ambrosi to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Ambrosi, A. G. to BCM
    - 1936 Mar 25 Postcard (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Ambrosi, A. G. to FTM
    - [1940?] Ti prego di gradire... 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Amicucci, Ermanno to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Angarano, Domenico to FTM
    - 1929 Apr 2 Postcard (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Angelini, Cesare to FTM
    - 1939 Jul 20 1 p.; [1942-43?] Oct 28 Ti scrivo in una... 1 p.; 1944 Mar Postcard (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Angelini, Cesare to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Anselini
    See: Box 14, folder 789
  - Antonelli, Giuseppe Rass to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Antonioni, Flora to FTM
    - 1940 Aug 3 2 p.; 1940 Aug 17 4 p.; 1940 Sep 18 card (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Apollinaire, Guillaume to FTM
    - [1910 Aug 24] Postcard; [1913 Jul 25] Postcard; in an envelope, with the following four postcards, labelled "Cartoline Apollinaire" and the dates, in the hand of BCM; 1913 Dec 20 Postcard; [1914 May 18] Postcard; [1917 Oct 28] Postcard; [1918 Aug 12] Postcard (Box 7, Folder 97)
      See also: Box 12, folder 608
  - Aramonte, Pippetto to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Aranha, José Pereira du Graça to FTM
    - 1926 May 24 Telegram in French (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Arcari, Paolo to FTM?
    - 1924 Nov 24 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Archipenko, Aleksandr Porfirevic to FTM
    - 1913 Oct 26 1 p. In French (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Ardemagni, Mirko
    See: Box 12, folder 598
  - Arishima, Ikouma
    - n.d. Calling card (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Armani & Stein, Rome to FTM
    - 1914 Jul 16 1 p. TLS; accompanied by FTM's receipt for a postal order of 15 Jul 1914.; 1914 Nov 12 2 p. TLS; on the verso, in blue pencil in hand of FTM, "ricevuto totale denaro".; 1915 Feb 15 2 p. TLS; notes by FTM on the verso and the bottom of the page (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - 1915 Mar 11 1 p. TLS; 1915 Mar 18 1 p. TLS; 1915 Mar 24 2 p. TLS; notes by FTM on the verso.; 1915 Apr 8 2 p. TLS; on the verso, in pencil in hand of FTM: "Mandare 382,50 a Armani".; 1915 Apr 16 1 p. TLS; Enclosure: bill.
  - Armani & Stein, Rome to Luciano Folgore
    - 1914 Aug 29 1 p. TLS (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Armani & Stein, Rome to Auro D'Alba
    - 1915 Jan 23 1 p. TLS (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Armao, Ermanno to FTM
    - 1926 Jun 26 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Armenante, Mattia to Prampolini, [Primo] Congresso Futurista
    - 1924 Nov 21 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Arte Fascista, Palermo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Artieri, Esther & Giovanni to BCM
    - 1940 Feb 5 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Aschieri, Bruno to FTM
    - 1942 Sep 27 2 p. On the verso, a letter signed "papà e Mamma di Bruno." (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Asinari di Bernezzo, Giuseppe Mario to FTM
    - 1937 Feb 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Associazione Nazionale Volontari di Guerra, Reggio Emilia to FTM's family
    - 1944 Dec 4 TL, signed by 6 people. (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - Astaldi, Maria Luisa to FTM
    - [1929 Mar?] 22 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Aurel, pseud.
    See: Box 14, folder 775
  - Azari, Fedele to FTM
    - No year Mar 31 2 p.; No year Apr 4 2 p.; No year Jul 19 2 p. photocopy only; No year Dec 27 2 p.; 1927 Apr 29 3 p. Notes by FTM to Mussolini on the verso of p. 1 and 3.; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram; signed also by Celesia, Galli, Perazzini, Penna.; [1929 Mar] 2 p. Enclosed, clipping dated 23 Mar. (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Azari, Fedele to BCM?
    - 1927 Apr 29 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Baccarani, Franco to FTM's family
    - 1944 Dec 3 Card (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - Badoglio, Pietro to FTM
    - n.d. Card; 1936 Jul 3 Telegram; 1937 Oct 17 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - Bagnaschi to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Baguttiani to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - Bailby, Léon to FTM
    - 1914 Jul 5 2 p. In French. (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - Balbo, Italo to FTM
    - 1928 Jun 20 TLS; Enclosure: TLS to Italo Balbo, from Ghulin d'Amdi(?) 3 p.; 1937 Feb 28 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - Baldetti, Guido to the Ente Artistico Italiano [Primo Congresso Futurista]
    - 1924 Nov 13? Postcard (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - Balestieri, Elio to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 2 p. TLS (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - Balla, Giacomo to FTM
    - 1922 Oct 6 Postcard (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - Balla, Giacomo to Umberto Boccioni
    - n.d. Avanti che andiamo bene... 4 p. (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Balla, Giacomo to an unidentified recipient
    - n.d. Anche la critica è stata... 4 p. (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Baravelli, Enrico to [Primo] Congresso Futurista
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Barbi, Luce Marinetti to FTM
    - n.d. Perchè sei così triste... 4 p.; n.d. Ti auguro di... 2 p. Notes by FTM on verso; 1929 Mar 22 Telegram; 1938, Christmas Postcard (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Barbi, Luce Marinetti to BCM
    - n.d. 2 p.; 1943 Dec 28 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Barbiera, Raffaello to FTM
    - [1921 Sep 3] Card (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Barbieri, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1928 Nov 28 2 p.; 1928 Dec 18 3 p.; 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Barblan, Guglielmo to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Barela, Attilio to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Bargellini, Piero to FTM
    - No year Jan 25 Quando io ricevei 4 p. (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - Barison, P.
    See: Box 14, folder 811
  - Barni, Ugo to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Baroni, Eugenio to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 26 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Barrès, Maurice to FTM?
    - n.d. Elles m'ont toutes... 1 p. [1907 Dec 2] Card (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - Barsi, Luigi to the Ente Italiano Artistico [Primo Congresso Futurista]
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram; signed "Barsi [and] Mazzoni"; 1926 Nov 23 Telegram; signed "Barsi [and] Mazzoni" (Box 7, Folder 138)
      See also: Box 7, folder 87
  - Bartoccini, Bianca to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Barzini, Luigi to FTM
    - 1930 Oct 28 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Baseggio, Cecco? to FTM
    - 1929 Jan 2 2 p. card (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - Bassi, Mario to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Bastianelli, R[affaele] to FTM
    - 1940 Oct 4 2 p. TLS, notes on verso in hand of FTM (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Bastianini to FTM
    - 1939 Apr 13 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Battistella, Darvino to the Onoranze Filippo Tommaso Marinetti
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Battisti, Gigina to BCM
    - 1943 Feb 26 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Battistoni to FTM
    - 1940 Nov 15 3 p. TLS with many sections crossed out in blue pencil (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Beaudin, Nicolas to FTM
    - 1909 Nov 10 2 p. In French (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Bedel & Cie. to FTM
    - 1933 Jan 31 1 p. TL signed by R. Viejo, in French; 1933 Feb 4 1 p. TL signed by R. Viejo, accompanied by a draft of a note (or telegram) in the hand of FTM to the Marchesa Casati (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Beer to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Beghini, Maria to FTM
    - n.d. voi sapete con quanto... 2 p. (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Belli, Carlo to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 25 1 p.; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Belli, Piero to FTM
    - No year Jan 14 3 p. Includes a copy of a letter from I. Cappa to FTM copied by Belli.; No year Sep 6 3 p.; No year Dec 28 2 p.; 1921 Aug 18 3 p.; 1921 Aug 24 1 p. (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - 1921 Aug 25 2 p.; 1921 Nov 8 2 p.; 1921 Dec 24 1 p.; 1922 Jan 16 Postcard; 1922 Feb 11 2 p.; 1924 Nov 21 2 p.
  - Bellocchi, Ugo to FTM
    - 1940 Sep 7 3 p. (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Bellonzi, [Fortunato] to FTM
    - No year Dec 28 2 p. On verso, notes in hand of FTM (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Beltramelli, Antonio to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Beltramelli, M. to FTM
    - 1919 Sep 8 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - Benco, Silvio to FTM
    - n.d. Sabato alla tua... 4 p.; No year Oct 24 5 p.; No year Nov 25 1 p.; No year Dec 19 4 p.; 1939 Feb 24 2 p.; 1939 Nov 23 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Benfereri, Cari
    See: Box 17, folder 1092
  - Berchet, Federico Pinna to BCM
    - 1945 Jan 3 2 p. Enclosure: "Passione Futurista", poem, blue typescript, signed and dated by F.P. Bercher; 1945 Jan 2. 5 p. (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - Bernard Valère to FTM
    - 1908 May 17 1 p. In French (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Bernstein, Henry to FTM
    - 1909 Aug 31 2 p. In French (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Bertinetti, Giovanni to FTM
    - 1909 Oct 12 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Bertoglio, Mario Annunzio to Marinetti family
    - [1944] Dec [3] 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Bertollo, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Bertoni, Giulio to FTM
    - 1940 Feb 22 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Bertozzi, Renzo to FTM
    - 1922 Sep 19 1 p. Also 4 lines signed Verona (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Bertozzi, Renzo to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 9 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 167)
      See also: Box 10, folder 481
  - Bertrand, Pierre to FTM?
    - 1908 Jul 22 2 p. Signed "Pierre Bertrand, Secrétaire", for Francis de Croisset. (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Bertuetti, [Eugenio] to FTM
    - 1940 Sep 27 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Bevilacqua, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Bianchi, A. L. to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 4 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Bianchi, Camillo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Bianchi, Giovanni to the Presidente Primo Congresso Futurista Italiano
    - 1924 Nov 19 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Bianchi, Umberto to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 8 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Bianchi, Virgilio to FTM
    - [1924? Nov?] nel giorno in cui l'Italia Ufficiale... 1 p. On the verso, in the hand of FTM, V. Bianchi's address. (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Bice
    See: Box 10, folder 473
  - Biennale di Venezia
    See: Box 13, folder 681
  - Biggini, Carlo Alberto to FTM's family
    - 1944 Dec 4 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Bignone, Ettore to FTM?
    - 1939 May 14 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Binazzi, Bino to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 24 Telegram; signed also by Francesco Meriano, Aldo Valori. (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Bineiasi?, Bice to BCM
    - [1929] Mar 23 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Bini, G. to FTM
    - 1919 Mar 6 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Birot, PA
    See: Box 7, folder 80
  - Biscioni, Ottorino to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 27 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Blanc, Alberto [Gian Alberto] to FTM
    - 1925 Mar 3 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Bocchetti, Federico to FTM
    - 1942 Sep 6 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Boccioni, R. Amelia Callegari to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Bois, Jules to FTM
    - n.d. J'ai lu aussitôt le beau... 1 p. In French n.d. Pouvez-vous venir demain... Written on the verso of an envelope addressed to Bois in the hand of FTM.; 1908 tout à fait désolé de ne pouvoir... 1 p.; 1908 Jan 22 1 p. card.; 1908 Apr 25 Postcard; 1909 Sept 14 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Boito, Arrigo to FTM
    - 1905 Dec 5 1 p. 1907 Dec, card (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Boldini, Giovanni to FTM
    - 1921 Feb 23 2 p. Signed Boldini only. (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Bolelli, Tristano to FTM
    - n.d. Vi saremmo grati se voleste... 2 p. On the verso, a 14 line definition of "intonarumori" in pencil, in FTM's hand. (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Bolza, Giorgio to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Bolzon, Piero to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Bompiani to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Bona-Sortino
    See: Box 16, folder 1023
  - Bonardi, Dino to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Bonarelli, A to FTM
    - 1940 May 27 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Boncompagni-Ludovisi, Francesco, Prince of Piombino, Governor of Rome to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - Boni, Irene Maria to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25, card (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Bonifacio
    See: Box 9, folder 280
  - Bonino, Giovanni Battista to FTM
    - n.d. Ho avuto il fascicolo... 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Bonomi, Gino to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. Written on verso of photograph of Bonomi and family. Another photograph of a house is included (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 25 2 p. Borgese's address written on verso in hand of FTM.; 1930 Oct 19 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Borgese, Maria [Freschi-] to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Boris, to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram; signed "Dottor Boris" (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Boselli, Paolo to FTM
    - 1930 Dec 3 2 p. TLS (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Bot, Oswaldo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 24 1 p. Card; 1929 Mar 27 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - Botelli, Luisa to BCM
    - [Dec 1944?] Per quanto sapessiche... 2 p. Condolence (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Botta, Gustavo to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 24 Telegram; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - Bottai, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram; 1929 Nov 1 p. card.; 1937 Oct 19 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 205)
  - Bottari, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1940 Jul 30 3 p. (Box 8, Folder 206)
  - Bottari, Giuseppe to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 5 1 p. Enclosure: "Omaggio a Marinetti," by Giuseppe Bottari, Il Secolo XIX. (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - Bottini, Pietro to FTM's family
    - 1944 Dec 5 1 p. TLS (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Bottone, Umberto (Auro d'Alba pseud.) to FTM
    - 1919 Jan 24 3 p. Accompanied by a 5 page AMS list (of his works?) (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Bottone, Umberto to FTM's family
    1944 Dec 4 Telegram
  - Bouvier, Piera to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Bracci
    See: Box 10, folder 468
  - Braga, Alzira to FTM?
    - [1924? Nov?] Che la Festa al poeta vivicatore... 1 p.; 1924 Nov 19 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - Bragaglia, [Anton Giulio] to FTM
    - n.d. Va bene. Come vuoi! pero... 2 p.; n.d. Io non capisco perchè... 2 p. Card; 1924 Nov 23 Telegram; 1924 [Nov 24?] Un affettuoso saluto... Telegram; signed "Bragaglia, Comandini [and] Luciani" (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - Bragaglia, Carlo Ludovico to FTM
    - n.d. Anton Giulio non sta a parigi... 1 p.; n.d. Abbiamo passato momenti... 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Brignori, Orlando to FTM
    - 1940 Sep 11 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - Brizzi, Carlo to FTM
    - n.d. perdonate il mio silenzio. 3 p.; 1939? Jan 14 Telegram; 1939 Feb 3 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Brizzi, R. Enrico to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Brizzolesi, Vittorio to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Brochon? to FTM
    - [1902 Oct 1] 2 p.; 1902 Oct 9 2 p. card; 1903 Jul 18 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 218)
  - Brunati, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - Buccafusca, Emilio to FTM
    - 1940 Jul 18 1 p.; TLS 1940 Sep 29 2 p. TLS; 1942 Jul 25? 2 p. At bottom of page 2 addresses in the hand of FTM and author. (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Bucher (?), Arturo and Lily to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Buffarini Guidi, Guido to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 4 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Busacca, Nelle? to BCM
    - 1950 Apr 24 4 p. 2 page TLS, accompanied by 2 p. poem entitled "Alba".; 1950 May 27 3 p. 1 page TLS accompanied by 2 p. poem entitled "Canzone di Primavera" (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Busetto, Amorea to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram, signed "Busetto" only [1943?] Dec 3 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Buzzauca, Dionigi to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 24 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - Buzzi, Paolo to FTM
    - 1906 Jan 26 8 p. p. 6 and 7 have lines crossed out in blue pencil.; 1910 Oct 28 7 p.; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - Buzzi, Paolo to BCM
    - 1940 Jan 29 Telegram; signed Maria [and] Paolo Buzzi (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Buzzi, Paolo to Umberto Notari
    - 1934 Apr 15 3 p. (Box 8, Folder 228)
  - Cabrolari, Andreina to FTM
    - 1920 Sep 8 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 229)
  - Cafaro, Gaetano to FTM
    - 1936 May 19 1 p. TLS; 1936 Jul 17 1 p. TLS; 1936 Jul 29 2 p. TLS (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Caiani, Carla Caillot
    See: Series I, Box 2, folder 33
  - Caille, Baela to FTM?
    - 1912 May 31 2 p. In French; upper left corner missing (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Caldanzano, Luigi to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 1 p. card (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - Caldera, Carlo to FTM
    - 1940 Jan 6 3 p. (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - Calderini, Guido to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram; 1940 Nov 2 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 234)
  - Calderone, Gianni to FTM
    - n.d. [1929 Mar?] ti esprimo avanti tutto... 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 235)
      See also: Box 17, folder 1105
  - Caleca, Marino to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 236)
  - Caliceti, Vittorio to the Ente Artistico [Primo Congresso Futurista]
    - 1924 Nov 16 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 237)
  - Caliceti, Vittorio to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 238)
  - Caminada, Milda to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 239)
  - Campana to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 Telegram signed also by Fabbri (Box 8, Folder 240)
  - Campi, to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 241)
  - Campitelli, Franco to the Ente Nazionale Artistico [Primo Congresso Futurista]
    - 1922 Aug 19 1 p. TLS; 1924 Nov 21 Telegram; 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 8, Folder 242)
      See also: Series I, Box 3, folder 35
  - Candiago
    See: Box 9, folder 278
  - Candussio to the Comitato Onoranze FTM
    - 1924 Nov 21 Telegram; signed "Sindaco Tolmezzo Candussio." (Box 8, Folder 243)
  - Cane, Gian Battista to FTM
    - 1928 Sep 5 6 p. (Box 8, Folder 244)
  - Cangiullo, Francesco to FTM
    - n.d. Ricevute dei vaglia... Envelope only; n.d. domani ti spedirò le 4 tavole... 2 p. On verso of p. 2 drawing in pencil; n.d. Tutti gli auguri a te... Postcard; n.d. Innanzi tutto ti ringrazio... 3 p.; n.d. Scusatemi se questa volta... 4 p.; n.d. Ve ne ringrazio eternamente... 4 p.; No year Sep 10 ho ricevuto stasera... 4 p. On p. 3 and 4 drawings by Cangiullo in ink (Box 8, Folder 245)
    - No year Oct 4 Cadon le foglie su La Rimembranza... 1 p.; No year Nov 29 Di Marinetti ce n'è un unico... 4 p.; 1909 Sep 6 3 p.; 1910 May Ho ricevuto bramoso e lietissimo... 3 p.; 1910 May diverse volte ho scritto... 3 p.; 1910 May 13 3 p.; 1910 Jun 4 p.
    - 1910 Aug 1 2 p.; 1910 Nov 10 3 p.; [1914 or 1919] Sep 18 1 p.; 1919 Feb 21 3 p. Part of p. 2 circled in blue pencil; 1932 Apr 2 p.
  - Cannonieri, Leon Roberto to FTM
    - 1923 May 7 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 246)
  - Canonica, C to FTM
    - 1935 Oct 17 4 p. (Box 8, Folder 247)
  - Cantoni, Tullio to FTM
    - [1908] Aug 5 Postcard (Box 8, Folder 248)
  - Cantucci, Bruna
    - No year Jan 8 3 p.; No year Jan 17 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 249)
  - Cantucci, Ugo to FTM
    - 1915 Apr 26 2 p. (Box 8, Folder 250)
  - Canudo to FTM
    - n.d. ho avuto il tuo vaglia... 1 p.; n.d. perdona, ma soffro troppo... 2 p.; No year Dec 23 ti scrivo con grande... 4 p.; No year Dec 30 lunedì Sapevo che tu mi avresti... 3 p. (Box 8, Folder 251)
  - Capasso, Aldo to FTM
    - n.d. Vi ringrazio tantotantissimo... 1 p. (Box 8, Folder 252)
  - Capasso Torre di Caprara, A to BCM